#### Personal Information

FIRST NAME / SURNAME Mark Silverwood

ADDRESS 135 Serengeti Sands, Eldoret Street, Sunninghill, Gauteng

TEL 071 886 4259

**EMAIL** msilverwood@gmail.com

WEB <a href="http://www.marksilverwood.com">http://www.marksilverwood.com</a>

NATIONALITY South African
DATE OF BIRTH 14.Sep.1986

**GENDER** Male

#### **Profile**

An adaptable and responsible individual with a passion for developing solutions to unique and challenging problems. I possess a strong technical base in operations research (mathematical optimisation and simulation) and computer programming. I apply a research-focused approach to problem solving with attention to detail and revel in learning new tools and techniques. I enjoy working on prototype ideas, from concept to the finished working prototype; inclusive of all aspects of the job.

### **Interests**

- Operations Research
- Optimisation
- Simulation
- Prototyping
- Idea Development
- Web Development
- Application Development

- Neural Networks / Deep Learning
- Data Analysis
- Data Visualisation
- IoT (Internet of Things)
- User Interface Design
- Research

## **Work Experience**

**DATES** June 2012 - Present

**POSITION** Research Engineer

**DESCRIPTION** Application of Operations Research and Systems Engineering

techniques in the local mechanised mining sector.

**WORK COMPLETED** • PhD Research focusing on the optimisation of simulation models.

• Development of a web-based business process mapping and knowledge database application.

• Simulation consultancy work.

• Presenting post-graduate lectures on Systems Engineering and

Industrial Engineering.

**EMPLOYER** The Centre for Mechanised Mining Systems - Wits University

TYPE OF BUSINESS University Department



DATES January 2010 - December 2011

**POSITION** Data Technician

**DESCRIPTION** Analysis of logged race-car data acquisition for the series organiser with

the goal of performance equalisation.

**WORK COMPLETED** • Analysis and comparison of vehicle performance data.

• Development of software to compare data from various different logging

systems.

• Expert opinion on required adjustments to vehicle performance parameters (such as restrictor size, vehicle weight, boost levels).

• On-site technical support.

**EMPLOYER** Supa Production Cars

**TYPE OF BUSINESS** Motorsport Series Management

DATES January 2010 - May 2010

**POSITION** Research Technician

**DESCRIPTION** Optimisation of race-car dampers

**WORK COMPLETED** • Test-lab analysis of dampers on dynamometer.

• Use of vehicle dynamics software to determine desired characteristics

and settings for dampers.

**EMPLOYER** ADF Motorsport

**TYPE OF BUSINESS** Motorsport Race Team

**DATES** 2nd & 3rd Year Vacation Work

**POSITION** Intern (Research & Development)

**WORK COMPLETED** • Analysis of cracking turbochargers

• Research and testing for the introduction of a new

diesel engine

**EMPLOYER** Subaru Southern Africa

TYPE OF BUSINESS Auto-vehicle Manufacturer

# **Education and Training**

**DATES** 2010-2011

**QUALIFICATION AWARDED** MSc(Eng) with Distinction

**INSTITUTION** Wits University

**DATES** 2005-2009

**QUALIFICATION AWARDED** Bsc(Eng) Industrial Engineering (Hons)

**INSTITUTION** Wits University

**DATES** 2000-2004

**QUALIFICATION AWARDED** Matric (with six distinctions)

**INSTITUTION** Crawford College



# Additional Education Information

MSC RESEARCH PROJECT Application Of Stochastic Programming Techniques To Airline Scheduling

MSC POSTGRADUATE Operations Research Methods

**COURSES** Reliability Engineering

Production & Operations Management

**Quality Management** 

Value Engineering and Analysis Management of Technology

HONOURS DESIGN PROJECT Charter Airline Scheduling Model

**HONOURS RESEARCH** Item Shortages: Data Mining Diagnostics

**PROJECT**Skills

**INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING** • Operations Research

• Simulation Modelling

• Optimisation Modelling

• Design of Experiments

• Systems Engineering

• Lean Engineering

• Operational Planning

**PROGRAMMING** • Simio

• Gurobi

• HTML, CSS, Javascript

Python

• C#

• R

• Tensorflow

Polymer

• Mathematica

• Matlab

• Microsoft Office

• Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Sketch